Fang-Yi Yu

fangyiyu@seas.harvard.edu
http://www-personal.umich.edu/~fayu/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in the theoretical aspect of multi-agent systems. My work studies how multi-agent systems interact with information and explores how these systems can solve social problems, including learning, cooperation, and communication. My research focuses on 1) information elicitation, where each agent's information is correlated and used to acquire and aggregate their information; 2) social and economic networks, where each agent's actions only directly impact those around it. My recent and forthcoming work also looks into 3) dynamics of learning with multiple agents where each agent's decision affects data they aim to predict and each other.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Harvard University

Jun. 2020 - present

Postdoctoral fellow at Harvard School of Engineering and Applied Sciences

• Host: Yiling Chen, Gordon McKay Professor of Computer Science

University of Michigan

Sep. 2019 - May. 2020

Postdoctoral research fellow at School of Information

• Host: Grant Schoenebeck, Assistant Professor of Information

EDUCATION

University of Michigan

2014 - 2019

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering Division

• Advisor: Grant Schoenebeck, Assistant Professor of Computer Science

National Taiwan University

2009 - 2013

B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Mathematics (double major)

Publications

Unless specified otherwise, authorship is alphabetical. Conference proceedings are the main publication venue in Computer Science.

Selected Papers

[1] Information Elicitation from Rowdy Crowds Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu, Yichi Zhang

The 30th Web Conference

(WWW 2021)

[2] Learning and Strongly Truthful Multi-Task Peer Prediction: A Variational Approach Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 12th Innovations in Theoretical Computer Science Conference

(ITCS 2021)

[3] Escaping Saddle Points in Constant Dimensional Spaces: an Agent-based Modeling Perspective

Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 21st ACM Conference on Economics and Computation

(EC 2020)

[4] Consensus of Interacting Particle Systems on Erdös-Rényi Graphs

Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 29th Annual ACM-SIAM Symposium on Discrete Algorithms

(SODA 2018)

Manuscripts

- [5] Optimal Scoring Rule Design Yiling Chen, Fang-Yi Yu
- [6] Subspace Differential Privacy Jie Gao, Ruobin Gong, Fang-Yi Yu

Additional Peer Reviewed Papers

[7] The Limits of Multi-task Peer Prediction

Shuran Zheng (first author), Fang-Yi Yu, Yiling Chen

The 22th ACM Conference on Economics and Computation

(EC 2021)

[8] Cooperation in Threshold Public Projects with Binary Actions

Yiling Chen, Biaoshuai Tao, Fang-Yi Yu

The 30th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence

(IJCAI 2021)

[9] Timely Information from Prediction Markets

Grant Schoenebeck, Chenkai Yu, Fang-Yi Yu

The 20th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS 2021)

[10] Two Strongly Truthful Mechanisms for Three Heterogeneous Agents Answering One Question

Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 16th International Conference on Web and Internet Economics

(WINE 2020)

- [11] Limitations of Greed: Influence Maximization in Undirected Networks Re-visited Grant Schoenebeck, Biaoshuai Tao, Fang-Yi Yu The 19th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multi-Agent Systems (AAMAS 2020)
- [12] Information Elicitation Mechanisms for Statistical Estimation

Yuqing Kong, Grant Schoenebeck, Biaoshuai Tao, Fang-Yi Yu

The 34th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence

(AAAI 2020)

[13] Think Globally, Act Locally: On the Optimal Seeding for Nonsubmodular Influence Maximization

Grant Schoenebeck, Biaoshuai Tao, Fang-Yi Yu

The 23th International Conference on Randomization and Computation

(RANDOM 2019)

[14] The Volatility of Weak Ties: Co-evolution of Selection and Influence in Social Networks
Jie Gao, Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 18th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS 2019

[15] Cascades and Myopic Routing in Nonhomogeneous Kleinberg's Small World Model Jie Gao, Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 13th International Conference on Web and Internet Economics

(WINE 2017)

[16] Engineering Agreement: The Naming Game with Asymmetric and Heterogeneous Agents
Jie Gao, Bo Li, Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 30th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence

(AAAI 2017)

[17] Complex Contagions on Configuration Model Graphs with a Power-Law Degree Distribution Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 12th Conference on Web and Internet Economics

(WINE 2016)

[18] Sybil Detection Using Latent Network Structure

Aaron Snook, Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu

The 17th ACM Conference on Economics and Computation

(EC 2016)

[19] General Threshold Model for Social Cascades: Analysis and Simulations Jie Gao, Golnaz Ghasemiesfeh, Grant Schoenebeck, Fang-Yi Yu	
The 17th ACM Conference on Economics and Computation	(EC 2016)
Invited Talks	
Robust and Strongly Truthful Multi-task Peer Prediction Mechanisms for Heterogene The $6th$ Highlights of Algorithms	ous Agents 2021
Escaping Saddle Points in Constant Dimensional Spaces: an Agent-based Modeling I 2020 Junior Theorists Workshop, Northwestern	Perspective 2020
Learning and Strongly Truthful Multi-Task Peer Prediction: A Variational Approach EconCS Seminar, Harvard	1 2020
Robust and Strongly Truthful Multi-task Peer Prediction Mechanisms for Heterogene $The~70th~Midwest~Theory~Day$	ous Agents 2019
Dynamics on Graphs with Community Structures Santa Fe Institute	2019
Think Globally, Act Locally: On the Optimal Seeding for Nonsubmodular Influence Maximization	
Seeding and value of network information in social network applications, INFORMS	2019
Generalized Kleinberg's Small World Model IDSS, MIT	2019
Opinion formation, stochastic gradient descent, and gradient-like systems Algorithms & Complexity Seminar, MIT	2019
Teaching	
 EECS 376 Foundation of theoretical computer science, University of Michigan Undergrad-level, 500 students Graduate Student Instructor: Design homework and lecture notes, and host discussion every week 	Fall 2018 section
 EECS 574 Computational complexity, University of Michigan Graduate-level, 30 students Graduate Student Instructor: Design homework, and host discussion section every week 	Fall 2016
SERVICES AND OUTREACH	
 Program Committee Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2022 Conference on Web and Internet Economics (WINE) 2021 Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2021 	
External Reviewers for EC, WINE, AAAI, IJCAI, WWW, ICALP, FUN, SoCG, ICC Chief of Academic and Curriculum section for EEcamp, National Taiwan University	OCS 2012

Finalists, CSE Graduate Student Honors Competition, University of Michigan

Presidential Award, National Taiwan University

2018

 $2012,\ 2013$

AWARDS